Register of the Argentine subject collection, 1933-2003
Hoover Institution Archives
Argentine Subject Collection,
1933-2003
XX797
9 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 2 phonorecords, 1 videotape cassette, 9 phonotape cassettes (5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Speeches, bulletins, pamphlets, flyers, serial issues, reports, and sound recordings, relating to political, social and economic conditions in Argentina, and especially to the presidential administration of, and political movement led by, Juan Peron
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Argentina--Politics and government--1910-; Argentina--Economic conditions--1918-; Argentina--Social conditions; Peron, Juan Domingo, 1895-1974; Argentina; Phonorecords
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1933-1994. (Boxes 1-3)
  Reports, letters, position papers, pamphlets, bulletins, serial issues, flyers, election material, circulars, speeches, clippings, questionnaire, and miscellany
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1953-1985. (Box 4)
  Serial issues mainly relating to the Partido Comunista de la Argentina and the Peronist movement.
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1975-1992. (Record cabinet)
  Phonorecord of protest songs, videotape cassette about the Malvinas (Falklands) war, and audiotape cassettes concerning the Perons
Container List
- SUBJECT FILE, 1933-1994
  - General
    - Pamphlets
      - 1934-1955. Includes analysis of legal system and material from the youth wing of the Partido Socialista (Box 1., Folder 1)
      - 1964-1979. Includes material from extreme Right and Antisemitic tendencies (Folder 2)
    - Serial issues, 1971-1975. Includes material relating to trade unions (Folder 3)
    - Speeches, position statements, printed material, and questionnaire, 1933-1990 (Folder 4)
  - Armed Forces. Serial issues, Verde Oliva, 1992-1993 (Folder 5)
  - Economics. Speeches, pamphlets and articles, 1955-1992. Includes addresses by Raul Prebisch and material from the Fundacion Libertad, a conservative policy organization (Folder 6)
  - Elections. Reports, 1989 (Box 2., Folder 1)
  - Left (See also Peronism, leftwing)
    - General. Flyers, pamphlets, serial issues, and bulletins, 1963-1986 (Folder 2)
    - Manifiesto. Serial issues, 1976, published jointly by the organizations Orientaction Socialista, Movimiento de Activistas Socialistas 29 de mayo (M.A.S. 29), and Espartaco (Folder 3)
    - Partido Comunista de la Argentina. Pamphlets, 1974-1982, and undated leaflet. SEE ALSO: OVERSIZE FILE (Folder 4)
    - Partido Revolucionario de los Trabajadores (PRT). Bulletins and postion statements, 1977-1981. Also includes material from the armed wing of the PRT, the Ejercito Revolucionario del Pueblo (ERP) (Folder 5)
  - Ongania, Juan Carlos. Presidential speeches, 1967-1968 (Folder 6)
  - Partido Federal. Serial issue and election flyer, 1983 (Box 3., Folder 1)
  - Peronism
    - Leftwing Peronism. Serial issues and pamphlets, 1973-1977. Includes material published by the Partido Montonero (Montoneros) (Folder 2)
    - Peron, Juan Domingo, Eva and Isabel
      - General. Speeches, articles and serial issues, 1946-1993. Includes material relating to different Peronist governments and biographical material concerning Eva Peron (Folder 3)
      - Anti-Peronist material. Flyers, circulars, speeches, printed matter, and miscellany, 1943-1946. Primarily relates to the 1946 election and includes material from various political parties, including the Partido Comunista de la Argentina, the Partido Socialista, and the Union Civica Radical, as well as various trade union organizations (Folder 4)
    - Rightwing Peronism. Serial issues, 1973 and undated. Includes material from the Partido Justicialista (Folder 5)
  - Religion. Pamphlets, 1955-1979 (Folder 6)
  - Women. Pamphlet and position statement, 1949-1975 (Folder 7)
- OVERSIZE FILE, 1953-1985.
  - Serial issues mainly relating to the Partido Comunista de la Argentina and the Peronist movement. Includes a calendar depicting Eva Peron (Box 4)
- AUDIOVISUAL FILE, 1975-1992
  - One phonorecord, "Por el Fusil y la Flor: The Flower and the Gun," protest songs performed by Bernardo Palombo y Cantoclaro, 1975 (Oversize Record cabinet)
  - Phonotape cassettes. Speeches, songs, and other material relating to Juan and Eva Peron (Oversize Cassette cabinet)
    - "Canciones Peronistas," n.d.
    - "El Futuro es de los Jovenes," n.d.
    - "J.D. Peron y la Juventud," 1987
    - "Juan D. Peron: Fundamentos Filosoficos," 1984
    - "Juan D. Peron: Su Vida," (2 parts)
    - "Peron: F.M.I., el Socio que Nos Legaron," 1986
    - "Queridos Companeros: Peron y Eva Peron," 1983
    - "Y Que Sepan los Traidores," 1984
  - One videotape cassette, "La Leccion de Malvinas," 1992, concerning the Malvinas (Falklands) War. (Oversize Tape cabinet)
- INCREMENTAL MATERIALS (Box 5-10)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.